I didn't know why we'd received our lives
why we all had come into this world
I didn't know how to face the one beside
only I looked away and wandered where to love
only I looked away and wandered where to love though it was always by my side
though it was always by my side
If I have a tough, iron armor protecting the world
I wonder if I can see you, and beyond
I just want to be stronger than anything
I just want to be stronger than anything to hold you, all of, oh even the heart
to hold you, all of, oh even the heart
All the dreams end up as mere dreams, even if game's over
All the dreams end up as mere dreams,
even if game's over, I won't give up my hope
I won't give up my hope
Even a hope may be said 'Just that's a thought'
so I still want to reach for you hoping you live your soul
Only there's a truth
Only there's a truth. Living for making all the moments shine with proving all times. Just seeing your smiles,
Living for making all the moments shine with proving all times
Just seeing your smiles, that's my dream
that's my dream
Even if we're all even in the dark
Make My Day
Episode 12
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品  仅供学习交流  禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕  尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听&日校：小伍 gen   翻译&校对：mam 小江   时间轴：鸭鸭   压制：結城結衣
Where are we going?
どこに行くの
ヘリポートだよ
The heliport.
逃げるの？
You're running away?
客が大勢いてね　さすがに相手をしてられない
We're inundated with visitors.
We certainly can't entertain them all.
彼ね　彼が来てるの
It's him, isn't it? He's come here?!
だとして　どうする
What will you do if he has?
Kill me and run to his side?
僕を殺して逃げるのかい　彼の元へ
それは…
Well...
You're here because you didn't want to hurt anyone.
君がここにいるのは誰も傷つけたくなかったから
そのはずだろう
Or so I thought?
But, I...
でも　あたしは…
時間が惜しい　行くよ
Time is short. Let's go.
放して
Let go!
対応G2　彼女を放せ
Response G-2. Release her.
Roger.
ラジャー
Care to try?
試す？
Just shoot me and escape.
僕を撃って逃げればいい
そいつは何もしないよ
That one won't do anything.
覚悟があるならできるはずだ
If you have resolve, you should be able to.
10秒待つ
I'll wait ten seconds.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Zero.
Time's up.
時間切れだよ
In the end, that's all your resolve amounts to.
結局その程度の覚悟なんだよ
You're wrong.
違う
I'd have fired. But you're different.
僕なら撃った　でも君は違う
自分が汚れるのは嫌なんだ
You don't want to get your hands dirty.
Are you done now? Let's go.
もういいだろう　行こう
W-Wait!
待って
You've lost. Come on.
君の負けだよ　さぁ
放して
L-Let go!
No way...
嘘
Leonard?
レナード？
What's going on?!
何事だ
その銃を捨てろ
Drop the gun!
M-Mr. Kalinin!
カ…カリーニンさん
I-I didn't... mean to!
あ…あたし　わざとじゃ…
連れて行け
Take her away.
How's his injury?
傷は
Looks like it only grazed him. Such recklessness...
掠っただけのようだ
無謀なことを
Reinforcements?
援軍？
いや　あれも敵だ
No. Those are enemies, too.
In that case...
だったら
He read me!
読まれた？何者だ
Who is this guy?!
You still have far to go, Weber.
ウェーバー　まだまだだな
Now, how long can you keep running?
さて　いつまで逃げられるかな
通信妨害　ダメか
Communications are jammed. It's no use.
They're better at electronic warfare, too?
電子戦も向こうが上手
Talk about formidable.
なんて奴なの
新しい客だ　すぐ戻れ
We have new visitors. Return immediately.
Roger that.
了解
逃げていく？
They're running away?
No...
いや
Looks like something happened with the enemy.
敵も何かあったみたいよ
ああ　命拾いしたな
Yeah.
And it saved our butts.
それより　宗介が心配だわ
I'm more worried about Sousuke.
援軍？
Reinforcements?
いや
No.
More enemies?
新手の敵か
Chidori!
千鳥
Take off.
出せ
あれは…
Is that...?
It can't be!
まさか
千鳥
Chidori!
Sousuke!
宗介
Chidori!
千鳥
Sousuke!
宗介
Chidori...
千鳥…
Drop your weapon!
武器を捨てろ
目当ての女は逃したんだ
The girl we were after got away,
貴様に尋問したいことが山ほどある
but we've got a ton of questions for you.
Bind him.
拘束しろ
Yes, sir!
はっ
宗介　伏せろ
Sousuke! Get down!
やあ　ケサンを思い出すの
This sure reminds me of Khe Sanh!
おい　レモン　すぐ逃げろ
That's enough, Lemon! Get out of here!
作戦は失敗だ
The mission's a failure!
Sousuke Sagara!
We're about to drop the Laevatein!
相良宗介　今からレーバテインを落とす
Laeva... what?
レーバ…なんだと
レーバテインだ　もっとも本人の自称だがな
The Laevatein! Although it came up with that name itself!
This mech is...
この機体は…
Long time no see, Sergeant.
お久しぶりです　軍曹殿
Is that you, Al?
アルなのか
Affirmative. However, this mech
is known as the ARX-8 Laevatein.
肯定
ただし本機の名称はARX-8　レーバテインです
相良軍曹　あなたの戦争への復帰を許可願います
Sergeant Sagara, I ask permission to rejoin your war.
Of course. Permission granted.
もちろんだ　許可する
光栄です
I am honored. First, you must board.
まずはご搭乗を
さぁて
Now then...
Warning, enemy ASes approaching.
警告　敵AS　ベヘモスタイプ3機　コダールタイプ3機が接近中
Three Behemoth types and three Codarl types.
まずはひと暴れしますか
Shall we start by going a bit wild?
Why not?
いいだろう　行くぞ
Let's go!
Roger.
ラジャー
What's with this power?
何だ　このパワーは
失礼しました
Pardon me. This mech has not even
undergone a satisfactory test run.
この機体はろくな試運転も実施していないのです
なんだと
Say what?
それで　使えるんだろうな
So it's usable, right?
ラムダ・ドライバですか
The Lambda Driver?
Of course.
決まっている
I do not know. It has never been used.
わかりません　使ったことがありませんので
Well, whatever. I'm testing it!
もう知らん　試すぞ
Ready!
レディ
成功　なんとかなるものです
Success. We will manage somehow.
冷や汗ものだがな
You had me in a cold sweat, though.
接近警報
Threats approaching!
Our weapons?
武器は
お任せを
Leave it to me.
そのまま
Hold still.
補助腕だと
Auxiliary arms?
制御は私が行います
I will control them.
Honestly...
まったく
現在の荷重　推定1500トン
Current overweight estimate,
1500 tons. Escape immediately.
直ちに脱出を
Shut up!
うるさい
ほかに武器はないのか
Aren't there any other weapons?
こちらをどうぞ
Try this.
Demolition Gun?
デモリッション・ガン
165ミリだと
It's 165mm?!
Both its might and recoil are extraordinary.
威力も反動も桁外れです
It is impossible to fire without
a Lambda Driver, so exercise caution.
ラムダ・ドライバなしでの発砲は不可能ですので　ご注意を
Manual forced fire!
強制撃発
Ready.
レディ
Success, it penetrated the enemy's field.
成功　敵の力場を貫通しました
One more shot!
もう1発
すごい
Wow!
Are any left?
残りは
ベヘモスタイプ1機です
One Behemoth type.
It has abandoned combat and is withdrawing.
戦闘を放棄し　撤退中
追撃しますか
Shall we pursue?
It's outside this weapon's range.
この武器の射程ではもう無理だ
いいえ　可能です
No, it is possible.
What?
なに
デモリッション・ガン　ガンハウザー・モードに移行
Demolition Gun, switching to Gun-Howitzer Mode.
最大射程は30キロです
Maximum range is 30km.
いいだろう　試してやる
All right, I'll try it.
Direct hit; destroyed.
命中　撃破
危険空域を抜けました
We've cleared hostile airspace.
よし　高度はこのまま　北北西に向かえ
Good. Maintain this altitude
and head north-northwest.
Shit! Are we really safe?
くそ　本当に大丈夫なんだろうな
Don't move!
動かないで
バ…バカな真似はやめろ
S-Stop acting like a fool.
I'm serious! Turn us around right now!
あたしは本気よ　今すぐ引き返しなさい
You're unexpectedly lively.
案外元気なようだな
引き返して
Turn us around!
この人を　撃つわよ
I'll shoot this guy!
Go right ahead. He can't even
keep track of his own gun.
好きにしたまえ　自分の銃も管理できない男だ
本当に　本当に撃つんだから
I'll really...
I'll really shoot!
The way you shot Leonard Testarossa earlier?
さっき　レナード・テスタロッサにしたようにかね
A person who's not prepared
to shoot mustn't hold a gun.
撃つ覚悟のない人間が銃を持ってはいけない
Enforcing your will means hurting someone.
意志の強要というのはつまり誰かを傷つけることだ
君にそれができるのか
Can you do that?
あ…あたしは
I-I...!
私にはできる　だから今ここにいる
I can. That's why I'm here at this moment.
Tell me. Will I never get to see him again?
教えて　あたしはもう彼には会えないの？
Affirmative. Give me the gun.
肯定だ　銃を渡せ
じゃ　こうする
Then I'll do this.
Wait!
待て
I've had enough.
もうたくさん
Stop, I'll do as much as I can!
やめろ　できる限りのことはする
Take the helicopter back.
ヘリを戻して
それは…やはりできない
That... I still can't do.
レナードの手当が必要だ
Leonard needs medical treatment.
敵に撃墜される危険もある
There's also the risk of the enemy shooting us down.
So first, calm down and lower the gun.
だからまず落ち着いて　銃を下ろすんだ
Let me say goodbye, then.
じゃ　お別れを言わせて
なに
What?
The radio.
無線機
しっかしこれ全部宗介がやったのか　たまげたな
Still, Sousuke did all this?
I don't know what to say.
レーバテインだっけ　頼もしい機体ね
The Laevatein, it's called?
That's one promising mech.
If only we'd had it at Merida Island that time.
あの時メリダ島にもそいつがいたらな
何のことだ
What are you talking about?
後で話す
We'll tell you later.
それより相良　その機体なるべく捕虜には見せたくないんだが
More importantly, Sagara.
I want the prisoners to see
as little of that mech as possible.
Fairy Wings
了解
Roger that.
アル　ECS作動　不可視モードだ
Al, activate ECS. Invisibility mode.
無理です
That is not possible.
This mech is not equipped with ECS.
この機体にはECSが搭載されていません
なんだと
Say what?
Between unprecedented power and the Lambda Driver,
破格のパワーにラムダ・ドライバ
there was no space to load any
surplus electronic equipment.
余計な電子機材を搭載する余裕はありませんでした
There's hardly any electronic equipment!
電子装備がほとんどない
現代戦だぞ　正気か
This is modern warfare. Are you insane?
We can establish data links with our allies.
味方とのデータリンクは可能です
気を落とさずに頑張りましょう　軍曹殿
Let us fight on, and not lose heart, Sergeant.
余計な機材ならあるぞ
I can think of some surplus equipment.
何でしょうか
What might that be?
お前だ
You.
I should throw you in the trash and install ECS instead.
お前をゴミ箱に捨てて　代わりにECSを搭載すべきだ
その提案はナンセンスです
That suggestion is nonsense.
Without me, this mech is a useless--
私抜きではこの機体は役立たずの
新たな無線信号を捕捉　あなたを呼んでいるようです
I have picked up a new radio signal.
It seems to be trying to reach you.
Me?
俺を？
接続しますか
Shall I connect it?
やれ
Do it.
Sousuke?
宗介
Can you hear me? Come in.
聞こえてる？応答して
Chidori!
千鳥
千鳥なのか　どこにいる
Chidori, is that you?! Where are you?!
I'm all right, okay?
あたしは大丈夫だから
大丈夫なものか
Well, things aren't all right!
A lot happened on the way here.
ここに来るまでいろいろあった
I lost my way many times. But I came!
何度も迷った　だが来た
I did come! To rescue you,
and take you back to that school!
俺は来たんだ
君を助けて　あの学校に連れ戻すために
ココロに小さな花が咲いてる
kokoro ni chiisana hana ga saiteru
A small flower is blooming inside my heart,
どこにいるんだ　言ってくれ
Where are you? Tell me!
Sousuke... Stop it!
宗介　やめて
やめる？何のことだ
Stop it? Stop what?
I get it now.
わかったの
君からもらった枯れない花が
kimi kara moratta karenai hana ga
The unwithering flower you gave to me,
あたしが自由になろうとしたら
If I try to be free again... someone's bound to get hurt!
必ず　誰かが　傷ついて
そう　恭子だって　あんなことに
I mean, yeah! Look what happened to Kyoko!
信じることをもう怖がらないくらい
Chidori?
千鳥
shinjiru koto mo kowagaranai kurai
I was able to believe strongly enough in myself,
もう耐えられないの
I can't stand it anymore, so forget about me.
だから　あたしのことは忘れて
tsuyoku nareta kara
So I'm not afraid anymore.
強くなれたから
Chidori!
千鳥
Let's put an end to things.
もう終わりにしよう
This is the last time...
あたしたちはこれっきりで…
君に逢えてうれしかった
kimi ni aete, ureshikatta
I was happy meeting you,
...you and I...
これっきりで…
kodoku sae mo wakachi aeta
Even though I could only share my lonliness,
孤独さえも分かち合えた
今もこの空の下つながっていると
ima mo kono sora no shita tsunagatte iru to
Even though we're separated now,
やっぱり嫌だ
No, forget that.
sou omoeru hanarete mo
I still feel that we're somehow connected under this sky.
そう　思える　離れても
そんなの絶対に嫌だ
Forget all that! I don't care if I hurt somebody!
傷つけたって構わない
動かないで
Don't move! Let me finish speaking.
最後まで言わせて
Sousuke, I have an order for you, you hear!
宗介　あんたに命令するわよ　いい？
Chidori?
千鳥
Come and rescue me!
あたしを助けに来て
No matter what the cost!
どんな犠牲を払っても構わない
何人死んだって
Or how many die!
「ありがとう」も言えなかった
arigato mo ienakatta
I didn't say thank you...
何百　何万　何億死んだって構わない
I don't care how many hundreds,
or thousands, or millions die!
So you come and get me!
だからあたしを迎えに来て
約束さえできなかった
yakusoku sae dekinakatta,
I couldn't even promise...
あんたの全て
Make full use of all your absurd,
annoying, nonsense soldier skills!
非常識で　迷惑で　デタラメな兵隊スキルを総動員して
だけどあの日と同じ風がふいたら
dakedo ano hi to onaji kaze ga fuitara
However, like on that day, if the wind blows
No matter how dangerous your opponent,
どんなヤバい相手でもギッタギタにやっつけて
beat the crap out of him and come hold me tight!
あたしを抱きしめに来なさい
mata kanarazu aeru yo ne
Then I know we will surely meet again.
また必ず逢えるよね
You can do that, can't you?! Well?!
あんたならやれるでしょ　どう
ああ　できる
Yeah, I can do it!
I'll be there! Wait for me!
必ず行く　待っていろ
kimi ni aete ureshikatta
I was happy meeting you,
君に逢えてうれしかった
宗介　大好きだよ
Sousuke, I love you!
I love you, too.
俺もだ　愛してる
tsunaida te ga hokoridatta
And proud of our holding hands,
つないだ手が誇りだった
I'm so happy!
嬉しい
So the next time we see each other
for real, we had better kiss.
じゃあ　次にちゃんと会えたら　必ずキスしよ
ima wa betsubetsu no sora miagete itemo
Even though we look up to different skies now,
今は別々の空見上げていても
No holding back. No matter where we are.
思いきり　どんな場所でも
いい？
Okay?
You promise?
約束だよ
hora arukeru hitori demo
See? I can walk on my own now...
ほら　歩ける　ひとりでも
約束する
I promise.
Oh, but that part about millions dying was just figurative!
ただし　何億人っていうのは例え話だからね
Right. I know.
わかってる
I'll be waiting.
待ってる
Chidori?
千鳥
一杯食わされたかな
Did you pull one over on me?
What do you mean?
何のこと？
君が本気で死ぬつもりだと思った
I thought you truly meant to die.
That was no act, I was serious.
演技じゃない　本気だった
But...
でも
Now I've found my resolve.
今　覚悟したの
Man!
ったく
「宗介　大好きだよ」とか
"Sousuke, I love you!"
"I love you, too."
「俺もだ　愛してる」とか
もうやってらんねえよ
I couldn't take any more!
Just die already. Go to Hell!
もうお前死ね　死んじまえ
That's what you say after we're apart for half a year?
半年ぶりに顔を合わせてそれか
Look how much you've grown up, though.
いやいや　すごい成長じゃない
Your big sister's happy for you!
お姉さんは嬉しっ
Mao...
マオ
Anyway, Sagara, it's good to see you're all right.
とにかく無事で何よりだ　相良
積もる話は後でな
We have a lot to talk about later.
はい
Yes, sir.
Lemon.
レモン
無線聞いたよ
I heard you over the radio.
Oh, yeah. Um...
あぁ　その…
It's okay. Introduce me to your superior officer.
いいよ
君の上官を紹介してくれ
Circumstances brought us this far,
but now it's time for negotiations.
勢いでここまで来たけど　まずは交渉しないとね
上官
My superior, uh...
Mr. Sagara!
相良さん
Tessa.
テッサ
It's been a long time!
お久しぶりですね
よくご無事で
I'm glad you're all right.
Well--
あの…
テッサたん
Lil' Tessa!
I've missed you!
会いたかったぞ
わしもじゃ
So have I!
Lil' Tessa!
テッサたん
To be honest, it's been lonely!
正直寂しかった
What are these two doing here?!
なんでこの人たちがいるんです？
いろいろありまして
A lot of things happened.
Nurse!
看護じゃ　看護してくれ
Gimme some TLC!
こいつは無視しろ　看護はわしじゃ
Ignore this guy! I need a nurse's care!
Take them away.
お連れしろ
失礼します
何だ何だ何だ　何だこりゃ
何なのてめぇ
Get your hands off me!
離さんかい
Nurse!
看護　看護
TLC!
それよりも　彼を紹介します
More importantly, I need to introduce him.
He's a DGSE agent, and he saved my life.
DGSEのエージェントで　命の恩人です
Lemon, this is my...
レモン　こちらが俺の…
Lemon?
レモン？
Huh? What?
なに
彼女が俺の上司なんだが
Well, she's my boss.
Huh? I mean, you'll really...
でも　だって　この子…
紹介してくれるの？
...introduce me to this girl?
Hey...
おい
惚れたな　あれは
That guy's in love.
わかりやすいわね
Talk about easy to read.
またファンクラブ会員が一名追加か
I guess that's one more member in the fan club.
Captain, we still have not verified his intentions.
艦長　まだ彼の意志を確認していません
Oh, that's right.
そうでした
相良さん　私の隊への復帰を？
Mr. Sagara, will you rejoin my forces?
Yes, ma'am. I ask for your leave to return to my old unit.
はい　原隊復帰を許可願います
二人で逃げ場所探して
futari de nigebasho sagashite
Together, looking for a place to escape,
もちろんです
Of course.
The Tuatha de Danaan welcomes you back.
トゥアハー・デ・ダナンはあなたを歓迎します
Does that welcome extend to me
as well, Captain Testarossa?
歓迎というのは私もでしょうか　テスタロッサ大佐
走った天気雨の中
hashitta tenki ame no naka
We ran in a sunshine shower.
もちろんよ　アル
Of course, Al. I'm glad you're all right, too.
あなたも無事でよかったです
たとえば何かを失うとしても
tatoeba nanika wo ushinau toshite mo
Even if I lose something else,
ありがとうございます　大佐殿
Thank you, Captain.
守って行かなきゃ　ひとつだけは
mamotte ikanakya hitotsu dake wa
There's just one thing that I have to protect.
この世界に生まれたその意味を
kono sekai ni umareta sono imi wo
The meaning of being born in this world,
君と見つけに行こう
kimi to mitsuke ni yukou
Let's go and find out.
痛みさえも　抱えながら
itami sae mo kakaenagara
Holding on, even to our pain,
新しい景色　迎えに行こう
atarashii keshiki mukae ni yukou
Let's go and welcome a new world.
夕陽にかざした指先
yuuhi ni kazashita yubisaki
I shaded myself from the setting sun,
オレンジ映したプリズム
ORENJI utsushita PURIZUMU
The prism of my fingertips reflected orange.
自分のすべてを許せるくらいに
jibun no subete wo yuruseru kurai ni
For your sake, I want to become so kind...
優しくなりたい　君のために
yasashiku naritai kimi no tame ni
That almost everything else about me could be forgiven.
この世界に生まれたその意味を
kono sekai ni umareta sono imi wo
The meaning of being born in this world,
君と見つけに行こう
kimi to mitsuke ni yukou
Let's go and find out.
痛みさえも　抱えながら
itami sae mo kakaenagara
Holding on, even to our pain,
新しい景色　迎えに行こう
atarashii keshiki mukae ni yukou
Let's go and welcome a new world.